[Music]
hi everyone this is the usada pitch and
today we're sharing some exciting news
about a new feature on our play queen
tip center bringing us that information
is jeff cook who leads us out as legal
and investigations team as our general
counsel welcome to your first episode of
the pitch jeff
thanks so much avery it's great to be
here
so jeff tell us about this new feature
and how it works
absolutely so we're excited to announce
that we now have the capability of
receiving tips anonymously through text
messages
uh sent to what i hope will be an easy
to remember uh short code usada
and when we receive those texts we'll be
able to communicate back and forth with
the whistleblower anonymously and that
anonymity is guaranteed as it is all run
through a third party
very cool why did your team decide to
roll out this anonymous texting option
well we're dedicated to making reporting
of information to usada as accessible
and confidential as possible and by
allowing people to text information to
usada we're simply meeting people where
they are in terms of how they're already
choosing to communicate and share
information
that makes sense can you remind everyone
about the other ways to report tips and
why that's so important
sure other than the anonymous texting
service the primary ways we receive tips
are through our tip line
which is one eight seven seven play
queen
we also receive tips through our email
address play clean usada.org
and we receive tips through a web form
submission that you can access directly
from our website
you know if you're really so inclined
you can also mail a tip in to our
address in colorado spring springs
so the tips we receive and and the
investigations that follow are really
vital to the success of an anti-doping
program which in turn helps maintain a
level playing field and allows clean
athletes to thrive
some of usada's most high profile and
egregious cases of doping such as the
armstrong investigation have resulted
directly from whistleblowers coming
forward and sharing what they know with
usada
so i think there's a common concern
how can athletes and other members of
the sport community really know that
these systems are anonymous and secure
so with the anonymous texting platform
the personal information that the
whistleblower provides or can be
identified from their phone that's never
shared with usada because it's hosted
securely by a third party that runs this
same anonymized reporting service for
other organizations
including college and professional
sports usada will only know the identity
of the whistleblower if the
whistleblower chooses to provide that
information to usada so we hope that
that will encourage many more people to
come forward with the information they
have no matter how big or how small so
that we can all enjoy clean and fair
support
awesome well those are all of my
questions for today chef thanks for the
rundown on the new texting action
very welcome thank you for having me
thanks to everyone for tuning in we'll
see you soon for the next episode of the
usada pitch
[Music]
you